<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Raku Programming Language</title><link>/en/</link><description>Recent content on Raku Programming Language</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="/en/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>About</title><link>/en/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/en/about/</guid><description>Contributing to this website If you find a bug or want to contribute to this website, you can find the source code repository here. Acknowledgments This site owes its existence to:
Dozens and dozens of volunteers and drive-by contributors Larry Wall (Perl, Raku, Camelia, helpful feedback, content) Susanne Schmidt (design) Moritz Lenz (initiative, initial version, content, design, server administration) Carl Mäsak (Design, content, constructive bikeshedding) Daniel Ruoso (content, design fixes) Daniel Wright (perl6.</description></item><item><title>Community</title><link>/en/community/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/en/community/</guid><description>Internet Relay Chat (IRC) Much discussion happens on #raku, our IRC channel. This is the fastest way to get help.
Matrix There is a matrix room and also a space.
Discord If you prefer Discord for live chat, there is a Discord server available that is also bridged to the IRC.
Stack Overflow Many questions and answers marked with Raku tag.
Mailing Lists For more persistent discussions (and for the poor folks who can&amp;rsquo;t use IRC) we have several mailing lists.</description></item><item><title>Download</title><link>/en/downloads/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/en/downloads/</guid><description>Rakudo The most mature, production-ready implementation of the Raku language.
For information on how to download and install Rakudo on your operating system, view rakudo&amp;rsquo;s downloads Page.
Download Rakudo
Rakubrew rakubrew is a Raku installation tool. It allows to have multiple versions of different Raku implementations installed in parallel and switch between them.
Download Rakubrew
Ecosystem Module Manager If a module manager was not installed alongside your Raku implementation, or if it&amp;rsquo;s not available in your software repositories, you can download and install it directly:</description></item><item><title>Raku Compilers</title><link>/en/compilers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/en/compilers/</guid><description>Compilers Rakudo and NQP Rakudo runs on MoarVM and the Java Virtual Machine (JVM). It is actively developed on the Rakudo GitHub site. Download or compile Rakudo.
NQP is not a Raku compiler. NQP is a small subset of Raku used as a foundational tool to help write compilers (including Rakudo) and libraries.
Historical Compilers Niecza Niecza is a compiler targeting the Common Language Runtime (.NET and Mono). Its goal is to explore the static aspects of Perl 6 and the possibilities for compile-time optimization.</description></item><item><title>raku IRC channel</title><link>/en/community/irc/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/en/community/irc/</guid><description>#raku We discuss questions about Raku, how to install a compiler, proposals for small enhancements to the specification, ideas for new modules - you name it.
If you don&amp;rsquo;t have an IRC client installed, you can use your browser to connect to IRC.
If you prefer to chat on Matrix or Discord, our Discord server and matrix room are bridged with the IRC channels.
If you missed an interesting discussion on #raku - don&amp;rsquo;t worry, there are public logs available at irclogs.</description></item><item><title>Raku is optimized for fun!</title><link>/en/fun/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/en/fun/</guid><description> Ofun slides Perl 6 is my MMORPG Optimized for fun (IRC conversations) Lessons learned from open source communities My hobby: Troll hugging On Troll Hugging, Hole Digging, and Improving Open Source Communities The Principle of Charity: on the Importance of Using Constructive Arguments (orig. paper)</description></item><item><title>Resources</title><link>/en/resources/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/en/resources/</guid><description>For Newcommers The Raku Guide Learn Raku in Y minutes Raku Tutorials Perl and Raku Weekly Challenge Code Examples Rosetta Code, programming problems solved in Raku side-by-side with hundreds of other languages Raku Examples, lots of example programs written in Raku Screencasts szabgab.com, Raku screencasts Youtube Raku videos English Programming in Raku - Youtube videos English Youtube Raku videos Non-English Blogs Raku Blog Aggregator Rakudo Weekly Weekly changes in and around Rakudo Raku Advent Calendar help for contributors Misc.</description></item><item><title>STD and viv</title><link>/en/compilers/std-viv/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/en/compilers/std-viv/</guid><description>Note: STD and viv aren't actively developed anymore STD The Raku standard grammar is written in Raku, and specifies how a Raku program is parsed.
The source code can be found on github in the perl6/std project in the file STD.pm6.
Both STD.pm and viv are included in the STD package on CPAN.
viv viv should be read as VI ➔ V, where V and I are Roman numerals.</description></item><item><title>Tools+Whatever</title><link>/en/whatever/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/en/whatever/</guid><description>Editors, IDEs, * Editors and IDEs CommaIDE: designed specifically for Raku. Community edition available for free, additional features and more regular updates through paid Supporter Program. Atom: Raku syntax highlighter, a plugin that provides Raku highlighting. Follow the instructions in the package readme. Raku script runner See here how to configure both the above plugins, as well as others, to turn Atom into a Raku IDE. Works with the syntax highlighter listed above.</description></item></channel></rss>